<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Algorithmic!</title>
    <link>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Algorithmic!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ijj.li/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Self-hosting, Part 1: Overview of Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/secure_services_with_podman_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/secure_services_with_podman_part_1/</guid>
      <description>This post is Part 1 in a series on secure self-hosting.
In 2020, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a quest to build the perfect infrastructure for self-hosting services, both private ones for my LAN and public hobby projects. The goals I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking to achieve with my setup are simple:
 Automated: It should take a single command to provision a system, upgrade a system, and start or stop a service. Reproducible: If I destroy a VPS instance or physically fry a home computer, it should be trivial to start over on a fresh system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest from the Bottom Up</title>
      <link>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/rest_from_the_bottom_up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/rest_from_the_bottom_up/</guid>
      <description>This post was featured in the Art+Logic Blog.
The RESTful API has a funny place in the software development world: it&amp;rsquo;s widely regarded as the best general-purpose pattern for building web application APIs, and yet it&amp;rsquo;s also nebulous enough of a concept to cause endless disagreements within teams over exactly how to implement one.
Do I make my endpoint /company/123/ or /companies/123/? How about /companies/123/locations/ vs /locations/?company=123 ? How do I handle versioning the API?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eat Well and Sleep</title>
      <link>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/eat_well_and_sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 14:14:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ijj.li/posts/eat_well_and_sleep/</guid>
      <description>Sleep and diet have a huge effect on decision-making12, in a way that&amp;rsquo;s really difficult to recognize in the moment. When you&amp;rsquo;re tired, the chocolate looks more tempting than the running shoes; when your blood sugar is low, the TV looks more tempting than the job applications. If you&amp;rsquo;re sleep-deprived and you&amp;rsquo;re eating poorly, then trying to achieve an end goal is like running a marathon with a pair of koalas stubbornly wrapped around your legs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>